<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Husain&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://ahmadhusain.in/categories/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Husain&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://ahmadhusain.in/categories/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Price Optimization</title>
      <link>http://ahmadhusain.in/post/price-optimization/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ahmadhusain.in/post/price-optimization/</guid>
      <description>Price Optimization A demand model enables us to search for the optimal price by analyzing how the price changes increase or decrease the profits. In practice, however, we face numerous constraints and interdependencies that require much more elaborate and specialized optimization models to be developed. From [AI for Marketing Operation] Book, most of the constraints fall into one of the following three categories: supply constraints, demand constraints, and structural constraints.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mercari Price Suggestion</title>
      <link>http://ahmadhusain.in/post/2021-06-22-mercari-price-suggestion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ahmadhusain.in/post/2021-06-22-mercari-price-suggestion/</guid>
      <description>Mercari Challenge Mercari is Japan’s biggest community-powered shopping website. With the aim of realizing a society where global resources are used carefully and where everyone can live richly, the company has developed a flea market application ‘Mercari’ in Japan and the United States that allows individuals to easily and safely buy and sell goods. Mercari’s challenge is to build an algorithm that automatically suggests the right product prices to sellers on its app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Causal Impact on Leads Generation</title>
      <link>http://ahmadhusain.in/post/causal-impact/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ahmadhusain.in/post/causal-impact/</guid>
      <description>BackgroundIn the business process, the marketing team has a role to play in increasing the brand awareness of a product. When the marketing team’s efforts are successful to get the customer’s attention to find out the product, it will generate a lead. In a simple way, leads are people who are interested in a business product.
In the digital era, leads can be interpreted as people who visit websites directly or through advertisements, people who like, share content or product campaigns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text Classification with LSTM</title>
      <link>http://ahmadhusain.in/post/2018-09-21-text-classification-with-lstm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ahmadhusain.in/post/2018-09-21-text-classification-with-lstm/</guid>
      <description>Deep Neural NetworkBefore we further discuss the Long Short-Term Memory Model, we will first discuss the term of Deep learning where the main idea is on the Neural Network. So Neural Network is one branch of machine learning where the learning process imitates the way neurons in the human brain works. In Neural Network we know several terms, such as the input layer, hidden layer, and output layer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reproduce Economist Plot</title>
      <link>http://ahmadhusain.in/post/2018-09-15-reproduce-economist-plot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ahmadhusain.in/post/2018-09-15-reproduce-economist-plot/</guid>
      <description>Here is a tutorial how to replicate an economist publication plot using ggplot2. Please prepare the library required first and download the data on the link below to follow the code.
link for download the report: https://www2.deloitte.com/content/dam/Deloitte/cr/Documents/public-sector/2014-Social-Progress-IndexRepIMP.pdf
Load Librarylibrary(tidyverse)library(pdftools)library(ggthemes)library(ggpubr)library(tm)library(grid)library(ggrepel)library(scales)Import Datadatatext &amp;lt;- pdf_text(&amp;quot;data_input/2014-Social-Progress-IndexRepIMP.pdf&amp;quot;)Data Pre-Processingdatatext88 &amp;lt;- datatext[[88]] %&amp;gt;%read_lines()data1 &amp;lt;- datatext88[7:50]head(data1)#&amp;gt; [1] &amp;quot; 1 New Zealand $25,857 88.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantitative Trait Loci (QTL) Mapping</title>
      <link>http://ahmadhusain.in/post/qtl-mapping/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ahmadhusain.in/post/qtl-mapping/</guid>
      <description>BackgroundFood security is one of the main priorities in the National Development Plan. The availability of strategic food is highly relied as an effort to achieve food security. Strategic food can be defined as a food commodity that is related to the needs of most people. One example of a strategic food commodity according to the Indonesian Ministry of Agriculture is chili/pepper. Most of the time the farmers experience crop failure due to bacterial and fungal disease attacks on the roots and leaves.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
